pennyburners.com 2012-01-19

# PennyBurners Privacy Policy

Your privacy is important to us. To better protect your privacy we provide this privacy policy notice explaining our data collection practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used. To make this policy notice easy to find, we make it available in the main navigational toolbar, which can be accessed from any page of this website.

## **Information we Collect**

  1. **Cookies**  
When you visit PennyBurners, we send one or more cookies to your web browser. A cookie is a small, harmless piece of information that is stored in your browser. Only the domain which set that cookie can access the information from it. (i.e., other domains can't access cookies set by us, and we can't access cookies set by others) 
  2. **Server Logs  
** Whenever you access a file from our website, the server logs the following data: (i) Requested file name, (ii) Your IP address, (iii) Date and time of request, (iv) Your user agent, (v) Referring webpage (if any), and (vi) Size of the requested document. 
  3. **Social Account  
** In the process of creating an account on PennyBurners,  we are provided with your email address. This is done to verify your identity and that you are a real human being; not some unscrupulous bot submitting web forms across the internet. Also, each thread, post, and message you create on the PennyBurners Forum or Social Network is associated with your forum account & stamped with your IP address. 
  4. **Blog Comments  
** Comments can be made on the PennyBurners News Blog without any account registration. The standard visitor information like: IP address, email (not verified), name (not verified) and your website URL (optional) is logged against each comment you make on a blog post. 
  5. **Visitor Patterns  
** We use a server side visitor tracking program (Joomla Watch) to see how our website, website sections, and webpages are performing. (e.g. Unique Visitors, Page Views, Total Visitors, etc.). This service tracks individual IP addresses, the Operating System of the individual, the location of the individual (based on IP address), the referrer information, and what pages are viewed and how long they are viewed. This is not a service and only the administrators of PennyBurners can see this information.

## **How We Use Your Information:**

  1. **Email Addresses  
** Email addresses you enter while registering on the forum and/or while commenting on blog posts are used to provide you updates of any content which you have subscribed to. Occasionally, we send out newsletters and/or important announcements regarding the changes in website, ongoing contests, maintenance down times, etc. You email address is safe with us. We won't sell it to anyone! 
  2. **Passwords**  
The password which you use to log-in to the PennyBurners forum account is hashed and salted before being saved in our database. It is NEVER stored in a plain text format. This way, even we can't see what your password is. And that's why, in case you forget your log-in password, we can't retrieve it for you; we are only able to change it to something else. 
  3. **Visitor Statistics  
** Visitor statistics and data logged by the server and JoomlaWatch are used to improve our site. We can quickly see which pages are performing well and which of them are not. Some statistics like Total Visitors, Unique Visitors, Aggregate Page Views per month are released to potential advertisers. But no personal information about any of our users is ever revealed. 
  4. **Cookies  
** Cookies are used to store your personal preferences for a short time. They are used to customize the content that is served to you on the PennyBurners forum (primarily) and/or other site's sections. Cookies are also used to store your site log-in credentials. (So you may or may not face difficulties accessing member-only functions, if you login with cookies disabled in your browser) 
  5. **Data Security  
** Appropriate measures (user authentication, authorization, data encryption) are taken to ensure that the data we collect is safeguarded and secure from unauthorized access. Regarding the data submitted in the PennyBurners Forum: private profile fields can only be accessed by site administrators, and IP addresses attached to the threads/posts can only be accessed by site administrators and moderators. 
  6. **Accessing your Info  
** Wherever possible and feasible, we provide a way for you to edit and update your personal information. In the case of the PennyBurners forum, you can edit your personal information and site preferences via the UserCP (User Control Panel). The various options and setting groups available to you are explained below:   
 **UserCP » Edit Your Details**  
Edit your personal information like birth date, birth date visibility preference, website URL, your Location, Occupation, Hobbies / Topics of Interest, Biography, etc. All of these fields are optional and you can clear them out anytime you want.   
 **UserCP » Profile Privacy**  
You can select the user types who can access your user profile. Data which you can restrict is: Contact info, Profile picture, Visitor messages, Albums, Biography, Friends list, Recent profile visitor list and Group membership list. You can set the access level to: Everyone (Guests included), Registered Members, Users on your Contact list, Your Friends.   
 **UserCP » Edit Options**  
Various options are available to customize your PennyBurners Forum experience. The settings groups include: Log-in settings, Thread Display Options, Date / Time / Timezone selection and some Miscellaneous options like the Forum's color scheme / layout (if multiple selections are available).   
 **UserCP » Edit Email & Password**  
This is self-explanatory. You can edit the email address associated with the Forum account and the password which you use to log in. Please note that if you update your email address, you will have to verify that new address too. 

## **Any questions?**

  1. Have any. questions regarding the privacy policy and how we implement it? Feel free to contact us at Nick@PennyBurners.com / 832-596-7014.

Last updated 12/17/2011

Like 0  Please log-in to like this.
